# Dzmitry Baranau Senior Full-Stack Developer

# PHONE

+48(571)609-343

## **ADDRESS**

ŁÓDŹ, POLAND

#### URL

PORTFOLIO LINKEDIN GITHUB

# **EMAIL**

DIMABARANOV98@GMAIL.COM

#### **ABOUT ME**

Hey, my name is Dzmitry and I'm a Senior Full-Stack Developer. I have experience working with small product companies (with team of 4-8 developers) and big outsource companies (opportunity to work with different teams worldwide and use different tech stack). I write clean code, do reviews, familiar with best programming practices (SOLID, DRY, TDD), agile methodology and scrum workflow, I'm a quick learner and it's not a problem for me to hop into ongoing project and make a valuable impact. I've been running demos for clients, brainstorming the requirements for the product with the team and taking a part in choosing right solutions. Recently I had experience leading team and deliver web3 app from start to finish and succeed. I look for a place where I can grow as an engineer and as a person. I have interest in growing as an architect/team lead/managing position.

# **EXPERIENCE**

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, STANUM LLC; REMOTE DEC 2023—PRESENT Working on building product in space exploration and satellite deployment domain Using React (Typescript, Antd, React Query, Feathers API) on frontend. NodeJS (feathers, postgresql) on the backend.

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, FREELANCE; REMOTE NOV 2022-DEC 2023 Launched Web-Scraping bot for automated visa slots checks using NodeJS, puppeteer, telegram API, 2captcha api, provided results for the tour agency.

Lead team of engineers to launch NFT marketplace <u>nft-grimace.com</u>.

For frontend used Typescript, React, NextJS, Styled-Components, Redux, Metamask wallet api.

For backend used NodeJS, Express.

For smart contracts used Solidity, Remix.

For deployment used AWS (Amplify, S3, Route 53).

Managing team to deliver web app for tour agency (aviabaltic). Communicating with client, project manager, designers, searched for people to delegate different type of work.

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER, GLOBANT; MINSK DEC 2020-NOV 2022 Contributed in launching several web apps for different companies (Dapperlabs, Depop) <a href="mailto:nflatth:n

My main responsibilities where developing react components, managing app state, using rest api, writing backend (node.js, express), writing tests (jest), reviewing code, participating in daily meetups, demo at the end of a sprint, brainstorming frontend solutions and choice of tech stack, attending team buildings at the bar:)

Technologies stack: React.js, NodeJS, TypeScript, GatsbyJS, Next.js, Redux.js, Jest, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Apollo GraphQL.

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER, EPAM; MINSK DEC 2019-DEC 2020

Played a key role in developing and maintaining an online store used by Thomson Reuters to sell tax, audit, accounting, and finance products store.tax.thomsonreuters.com.

Created a well-tested React (TypeScript) components library, developed parts of application responsible for adding products to cart and caching in local storage, learned SSR framework that was used inside of Thomson Reuters company. Collaborated with different teams and conducted code reviews, ensured app performance by monitoring and optimizing code, communicated with scrum master.

Technologies stack: React, TypeScript, Material-UI, Redux.js, Jest.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, LASTING DYNAMICS; REMOTE NOV 2018-DEC 2019 Contributed to launch work management system app.roundrush.com.

Develop parts of the app (dashboard, drawer, login form). Improved app performance using google chrome performance analytics tools. Did code reviews, gain experience in working with fully remote team (majority of the team was in Italy, rest across the world)

Technologies stack: React, TypeScript, Material-UI, Redux.js, Jest, Apollo GraphQL.

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, DISCRETEMIND; MINSK APR 2018-NOV 2018 First position where I've been working as an intern, contributed with developing simple react components for the web3 app (yes, I had opportunity to explore blockchain technologies in 2018), was writing and expanding backend using go lang, assembling blockchain nodes (using raspberry pi).

Technologies stack: React, Typescript, Golang, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Linux, Docker, Blockchain.

INTERNSHIP, MINISTRY OF INTERNAL AFFAIRS; MINSK FEB 2018-APR 2018 Internship at the ministry of internal affairs where I have worked on developing app for automated Microsoft Word documents filling connected with existing spreadsheet.

Technologies stack: React, Redux, Typescript, Material-UI, NodeJS, Electron.

# SKILLS

React, Redux, JavaScript, TypeScript, NextJS, NodeJS, Express, Electron, GraphQL, Gatsby, CSS (including CSS-in-JS, Sass, and responsive design), HTML5, jQuery, Bootstrap, MUI, Web Accessibility, Jest, AWS (Cognito, S3, Amplify, Route53), Docker, Performance optimization, MetaMask.

# LANGUAGE

Russian - Native Polish - A1 English - C1

# **EDUCATION**

MINSK RADIO ENGINEERING COLLEGE, MINSK - COMPUTER SCIENCE, 2019